

PERSONAL INFORMATION

- **些 D. O. B.** 8th Feb 1984
- Gender Male
- Nationality Ukraine
- Travel status Single

LANGUAGES

- **English**
- **Arabic**
- Ukrainian
- Russian

SKILLS

Leadership Communication Flexibility Teamwork Financial Integrity Analytical Detail oriented Time Management

CONTACTS

- **1** +380 63 80 79 79 3
- ✓ maher2002@live.com
- ✓ mgradrenalineparktara@signu mhotels.com
- s mr.maher2002
- in https://www.linkedin.com/in/maher-hakim-b346a6ab/

MAHER HAKIM

PASSIONATE HOTELIER PROFILE

For the past 21 years, worked with Luxury International Hotels & Resorts, including "Starwood", "Frasers Hospitality", "Movenpick Hotels" & "LHW" in Europe, Asia and Middle East. My resume speaks to my history of decisive leadership as well as strong financial and operating results. Most notably, I have:

- *Turned unprofitable properties into consistently performing, multimillion-dollar organizations
- *Streamlined operations and eliminated duplicate functions to reduce costs and increase productivity and revenue
- *The value I bring to the hotels is broad experience spanning all core business functions with a primary focus on operations and finance. My success is directly attributable to my ability to unify organizations, initiate action, and deliver results.

EXPERIENCE

SIGNUM **HOTELS & RESORTS**

04.2021 - Present

6* ULTRA **LUXURY**

RESORT "DK" 01 2018 - 03 2021 Cluster Resort Manager, Serbia & BiH Incharge of pre-opening in Balkans region

https://signumhotels.com/

Owner Representative & GM, Ukraine & **Belarus**

Pre-opening of the Resort & General Management

- 4* luxury Resort & Spa 130 Rooms
- 4* luxury Serviced Apartments 44 suites
- 5* luxury Hotel and Spa 52 Rooms

ACHIEVEMENTS:

- Entire reorganization of the hotel
- Increase in EBITDA by 23%
- Cost reduction by 24%
- Growth of income by 37%
- NPS from 40% to 72%

https://derenivska-kupil.ua/en/

REIKARTZ HOTEL GROUP - CONSULTING

11.2014 - 01.2018

Chief Development Officer, CIS & Europe 41 properties in 5 European Countries

ACHIEVEMENTS:

- Growing "the Pie" from 30 to 41 hotels
- Auditing of 100+ Hotels in 20 countries

https://reikartz.com/en/

5*

BARTOLOMEO RESORT | 5* **HOTEL & SPA** COMPLEX **TSUNAMI**

09.2014 - 09.2016

Cluster Resort Manager, Ukraine

Managing operations of 2 Luxury 5* Resorts. 200 rooms, 8 F&B outlets, 2 Spa's

ACHIEVEMENTS:

- Cost reduce for 21% during 2 years
- Increase revenue for 48%
- Staff turnover reduced for 25%
- GSI raised from 7.1 to 9.3

https://bartolomeo.com.ua/en https://tsunami.com.ua/en/home It is all about heads, beds, and guest satisfaction in the hospitality industry. It takes an innovative and tenacious manager to face successfully the tremendous challenges confronting today's leading hotels. I have made a career out of turning around faltering properties, raising service standards, increasing organizational efficiency, and significantly improving bottom-line profits.

4* AL SAFA ROYAL SUITES

01.2013 - 09.2014

General Manager, Qatar

Managing (4+)* Business Hotel, 285 Rooms, with 2 F&B outlets and Spa.

ACHIEVEMENTS:

- Inrease the occupancy from 15% to 75%
- FO upsells growth of 85%.
- Reservation upsellings grow of 45%
- GSI raised from 6.3 to 8.9
- Improved Rooms Division Departmental Profit from 35% to 72%
- Increasing the ARR by 20% without compromising occupancy
- Commercial spaces lease contract for 28,000,000 USD for 5 years

https://www.alsafaroyalsuites.com/

5* LHW "SUPERIOR GOLF & SPA RESORT"

01.2012 - 01.2013

5* Golf Resort, 45 rooms & 4 Villas, 2 F&B outlets, Golf course & Spa

Director of Rooms & Acting GM, Ukraine

https://www.superiorresort.com/en/

5* FRASER SUITES (Preopening)

11.2010 - 12.2011

Director of Operations, Qatar

5* Hotel, 138 rooms, with 2 F&B outlets, Spa

https://doha.frasershospitality.com/en

5* LE MERIDIEN AL AQAH BEACH RESORT

03.2008 - 11.2010

Night Manager, UAE

5* Resort, 218 rooms, 5 F&B outlets & banquet facilities for 1000 quests

https://www.marriott.com/hotels/travel/fjrmd-le-meridien-al-aqah-beach-resort/

MEMBERSHIP

11.2014

NEW BRIDGE PARTNERS

International consulting company
Crisis Management and Rooms Divison
http://www.newbridgepartners.org/

EDUCATION

2006 - 2007

POST-GRADUATE IN BA & ECONOMICS

International Slavonic University, Ukraine The program is for 1 year, passed with HONORS and EXCELLENCE degree (Cum Laude), and a project

2002 - 2006

BACHELOR HOTEL MANAGEMENT

International Slavonic University, Ukraine